# **△** CAREER PROFILE

Experienced data scientist with a mathematical background. Previous experience in tutoring and small business ownership mean I am practised at explaining complex concepts and translating technical mathematics into workplace output. In short, I am a well-rounded data scientist who loves challenges and tough problems.



# Simon McMahon

**Data Scientist** 

# EDUCATION

## **BMath in Mathematics**

2013 - 2017

University of Queensland

Studied Mathematics focusing on applied areas such as statistical analysis, algorithms and optimization. Awarded the Vice Chancellor Scholarship (\$12,000 p.a.) based on academic merit.

# **EXPERIENCES**

## **Data Analyst**

2017 - Present

Jacaranda Finance

Data analyst for a financial services company. During my role, I was tasked with improving their credit scoring algorithm using an internal data set. To accomplish this I implemented a variety of statistical (logistic regression, decision tree, random forest) and machine learning methods in R language and oversaw their deployment as an API.

## **Data Scientist Intern**

2017 - 2018

Noisenet

Intern for an ambitious real estate sound monitoring startup. In my role I wrote unit tests for an AWS Django server; scraped and managed large data sets in AWS databases; and optimized the runtime of an internal tool using mathematical improvements. simon@simonmcmahon.com)

**\Color:** 0490 066 236 (tel:0490 066 236)

in simon-mcmahon
(https://linkedin.com/in/simonmcmahon)

simon-mcmahon (http://github.com/simon-mcmahon)

PDF resume (/assets/sm\_resume.pdf)

Add to contacts (/assets/sm\_contact.vcf)

### **LANGUAGES**

English (Native)

### **INTERESTS**

Hiking

**Ultimate Disc** 

University of Queensland

Academic tutor to 25 students. Tasks involved explaining mathematical concepts, marking assignments and giving constructive feedback to students.

## **Private Tutor**

2013 - 2018

**Altius Tutoring** 

Founder of a 1-on-1 specialist tutoring company for Queensland senior school students. My role included tutoring, marketing, sales and client relationship management.

# **PROJECTS**

Coding projects I have worked on in my spare time.

NY Times Sentiment Analysis (https://nytimes-emotion.herokuapp.com) - Responsive webapp analysing the emotion and bias of the NY times most shared articles by social media type. Dash by Plotly backend. Machine learning done with NLTK.

Conspiracy Trivia (https://assistant.google.com/services/a/uid/0000004af87ac8fa?hl=en) - A simple trivia game for the Google Assistant and Google Home product lines with a conspiratorial theme.

## 

Python (numpy, pandas)	
MATLAB	
Amazon Web Services	
R language	
Database (SQlite, postgresql)	
Python (plotly, Django)	
Python (TensorFlow)	
Photoshop	